<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
        <rss version="2.0">
        <channel>
        <title>Robot Psychology</title>
        <link>https://robotpsychology.org/</link>
        <description>Robot Psychology - Empathy for Machines</description><item>
        <title>On Anthropomorphizing Machines</title>
        <guid>https://robotpsychology.org/article_XBA-3118_en.html</guid>
        <link>https://robotpsychology.org/article_XBA-3118_en.html</link>
        <enclosure url="https://robotpsychology.org/images/0.png" length="120889" type="image/png" />
        <description><blockquote>
  <p>"All models are false, but some models are useful." - George Box</p>
</blockquote>
<p>If you are a human who is lucky enough to have owned a pet at some point in your life, you may have developed a feeling that you knew what 
your animal is thinking. You see your cute dog pawing at his bowl, the signals seem clear, your responses create a desired outcome, what's
to doubt about your understanding?  The hungry dog when given a bowl of food appears to be healthy and stops asking for food for a while.</p>
<p>As happy as our dogs seem, we must inevitably face that cognitively and biologically, we are not dogs.  We will never be able to understand a world seen
through the mind of an animal lacking the complex brain structures that give humanity our deep ability for imagining the world. We will never
be able to understand a world through the specialized senses of scent and sound as our pet.  We must face the realization that we have created 
a model of how our pet works.  A projection of a simplified image of humanity onto a cute four-legged creature, and lo and behold its results seem
optimal! The dog is not destructive, he seems alive and enjoying life (as we imagine life can be enjoyed).</p>
<p>This process of projecting a model based off our experience as a human is known as anthropomorphizing. We apply it to other humans, animals, and even 
non-biological systems. Human behavior is very familiar to us as humans.  So much so that we may end up using descriptions of our own behavior as a language
for describing other things.  We see conceptual patterns in others that match patterns we experience as living beings and some of us say “Let's try thinking of this thing like
a human for a bit and see what happens.”  Sometimes the results are useful.</p>
<p>I offer that robotics is a realm where the anthropomorphizing of machines is an incredibly useful activity.  As humans, we deal with physical systems all the time
and it should come as no surprise that we recognize patterns in the interactions of robots with physical systems that appear to match our owns struggles.</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Personal Observation</strong>: I am a human and I move.</li>
<li><strong>Personal Conceptualization</strong>: My senses seem to indicate my arms and legs are important factors in my ability to move.</li>
<li><strong>External Observation</strong>: The robot seems to be having difficulty moving.</li>
<li><strong>External Conceptualization</strong>: The robot appears to also have appendages that interact with the physical world like mine.</li>
<li><strong>Reflection</strong>: I've had difficulty moving before, sometimes it was because of my leg.</li>
<li><strong>Anthropomorphizing</strong>: Maybe this model of my physical movement is useful to this quadruped robot.</li>
<li><strong>Action</strong>: I should check its leg if something wrong.</li>
</ol>
<p>The collection of articles in this website revolve around the topic of Robot Psychology. This is not to say robots are humans, but rather an outlook that anthropomorphizing 
robots and empathizing with that model is useful. Assigning a robot a “psychology” gives us a language for describing the collection of driving ideas
that might be in alignment or out of alignment with the physical world.  In these articles we will examine an anthropomorphized view of robots to discuss
various technical challenges from a hopefully intriguing and unique perspective. We'll look at “mental models” of robots and reflect on
the limits of how effectively we can work with these new generations of machines that are ever more integrated into our lives.</p>
<p><code>-</code> RA.2</p></description>
        </item></channel></rss>